mvm.com 2012-05-10

# My Virtual Model - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

This statement will tell you how we use your personal information on the My Virtual Model Inc. Web sites (including www.myvirtualmodel.com and all sub-domains), and throughout the My Virtual Model™ affiliate network. We made this statement as broad and clear as possible. Please review it to learn more about our practices. 

This statement was last updated: September 5th, 2006

Users under 13 years of age should read our Privacy policy for kids.

This part applies to teens and adult users.

  * Who are we?
  * What personal information do we collect?
  * How do we use this information?
  * With whom might we share this information?
  * What choices are available to you?
  * What security controls are in place?
  * How to update your information?
  * How to reach us?

Back to top

## Who are we?

My Virtual Model Inc. (MVM) is the software company that brings you the My Virtual Model™ services. Founded in 1990, we are a Montreal-based Canadian company. We offer our services free of charge to all users. We may also create, use, or buy other technologies overtime. 

MVM affiliates are owners of MVM-enabled Web sites that use the My Virtual Model™ technologies to give you personalized services such as 3D modeling, size and fit suggestions, style advice, postcards, etc. Please note that not all MVM services may be available at every affiliate's Web site. All affiliates of the MVM network have their own privacy policies that you can review on their Web sites. 

Back to top

## What personal information do we collect?

Our registration forms and measurement forms ask for information about you and how you would like to use our services. Specifically, we ask for your e-mail address, ZIP code or postal code, gender, age group, measurements, skin tone, hairstyle, and/or other physical features or preferences, which are used to tailor the services to your needs. We will keep your information strictly confidential. 

Back to top

## How do we use this information?

### Demographic data

We use information about your gender and age group to provide you with the service you are requesting from us. We will use your ZIP code or postal code, combined with a demographic database, to get a broad idea of who our users are. We will also use this information to draw anonymous statistics. 

### Measurement and facial data

You can use MVM services on any MVM-enabled Web site set to process your request. For example, if you want to use our service on a special size e-shopping site, you must provide specialsize measurements in order to use the service at this site. You may always visit the site as an unregistered visitor, or without using the MVM services. We will also use this information to draw anonymous statistics. 

### E-mail address

When you register for the first time, we may send a confirmation message to your mailbox. You can choose to use this same address to subscribe to our newsletter or other services we may offer. We may also use your e-mail address as an internal identifier. This is sometimes useful for addressing an issue should you contact our help desk. 

### Statistics

Usage data gathering and anonymous statistical analysis are part of the data management practices necessary in order for us to offer you our services. This data is not identifiable to any individual. 

We gather statistical data on visits made to the various pages of our site. We monitor how our servers perform to ensure that users can always enjoy visiting our site. We also gather statistical data from the various MVM-enabled Web sites in order to charge our affiliates for the use of our software. We do not share your personal information with the affiliates. We send summaries of statistical data to each MVM affiliates on a regular basis in order to help them to manage their own sites. We may also use these combined statistics for research purposes, and to develop better services for our users and affiliates in the future. 

### Data sharing

MVM services and links to our registration forms are available at various Web sites on the Internet. When you first register for our services, we store your information on the MVM central servers. 

This feature allows you to reuse your information at several Websites without revealing your personal information to the affiliate. There is no direct data sharing between My Virtual Model Inc. and any of our affiliates. MVM affiliates cannot access your information unless you give us your consent. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a text file that a Web server sends to your browser for management purposes. It can neither run programs, nor put a virus into your system. 

Some MVM services use a temporary cookie in order to personalize your experience. This type of cookie lets the server know that you have logged in. Without it, the server would have to ask you repeatedly for your user login information. If you choose to do so, you can also have our server send you a permanent cookie. This type of cookie will allow you to automatically log into an MVM service on your next visit to any MVM-enabled Web site. 

### Postcard service

To use the postcard service, you must enter one or more recipients' e-mail addresses. We will only use these addresses once to send the recipients an e-mail notice, so they can fetch your postcard on our Web server. We will not keep their addresses. 

If you send a postcard to many people at once, each person will get a separate notice. This ensures that no one can see the others' addresses. We will keep your postcard for 20 days only, after which time we will delete it. 

### User correspondence

You can send e-mail messages to our help desk, send your comments, or contact us for business reasons through various e-mail forms. We may ask for some personal information, such as your name and your e-mail address. We will use it only to answer your request. We will keep your e-mail address and message for our records. 

We answer questions about fashion anonymously. We publish selected user questions and answers on our Web site on a monthly basis. We will neither contact you, nor keep your e-mail address. We will strip your message of any personal information, and keep only the content for our records. We may use the content of some messages in promotional copy. 

Back to top

## With whom might we share this information?

We will not share your personal information with our affiliates without your consent. You might want to review each affiliate's privacy policies before using our services at their sites. You can find a complete listing of our current affiliates on the www.myvirtualmodel.com Web site. 

Occasionally, we may have to disclose or report someone's personal information, if regulators or other authorities require it. 

Back to top

## What choices are available to you?

We do not make secondary uses of your personal information other than those described in this statement. We only use your information for providing you with our main services or improving these services through research studies that we may conduct now or in the future. 

We offer our services while respecting your choices. You can review your options on the www.myvirtualmodel.com Web site. To cancel any service, simply access your user profile and either edit your choices, or delete your user profile altogether. 

Deleting your My Virtual Model™ user profile will have no effect on the customer accounts you may have created with any of our affiliates. If you want to close a customer account at any affiliated Web site, please visit that site directly. 

Back to top

## What security controls are in place?

We use data scrambling to send data over the Internet. We have also put in place methods to protect the information we collect and use in our company. We have chosen a first-class partner to host our Web site and central servers, which uses industry-leading security standards. 

Please, keep your password secret, so others do not access your user profile. 

Back to top

## How to update your information?

You can review, edit, or delete your personal information and options by accessing your user profile on the www.myvirtualmodel.com Web site. 

Back to top

## Privacy policy for kids

This part applies to users under 13 years of age.

  * Kid's profile
  * MVM-enabled Web sites
  * Statistics
  * Postcard service
  * User correspondence

### Kid's profile

We offer our services free of charge to all users. If you are a kid, you can use these services without giving out any personal informationsuch as your name or e-mail address. Your username and password are yours. Please keep them secret. 

We take for granted that users providing kid's measurements are less than 13 years of age. This ensures we will never collect personal information from users who must not give it out. 

### MVM-enabled Web sites

MVM affiliates are owners of MVM-enabled Web sites that use the My Virtual Model™ technologies to give you personalized services such as 3D modeling, size and fit suggestions, style advice, postcards, etc. Please note that not all MVM services may be available at every affiliate's Web site. All affiliates have their own privacy policy for kids, which you should review with your parents. 

If an affiliate offers you to open a customer account, remember that you are now dealing with this affiliate only, and not with My VirtualModel Inc. 

### Statistics

We do not collect personal information from kids. Your user profileis unidentified. No one has access to your data. We give only summaries of statistics, or totals, to our affiliates. This helps them to manage their own sites. 

### Postcard service

Everyone using our postcard service has to put a sender's e-mail address. However, if you use it when logged-in as a kid, we will not keep the sender address either. Once we have sent a notice to each recipient, we delete all and every e-mail addresses from our server. 

If you send a postcard to many people at once, each person will get a separate notice. This ensures that no one can see the others' addresses. We will keep your message for 20 days only, after which time we will delete it. 

### User correspondence

You can send a message to our help desk, or send your comments through various e-mail forms. We may ask for your e-mail address. We will use it only to answer your request. We will not keep your address. We will strip your message of any personal information, and keep the content for our records. We may use the content of some messages in promotional copy. 

Back to top

## How to reach us?

If you want to send us your comments, questions, or suggestions about this policy, please write to: 

Privacy Custodian: [privacy@myvirtualmodel.com](mailto:privacy@myvirtualmodel.com)

You can reach us at:

Privacy Custodian

**My Virtual Model Inc.**  
80 Queen street, Suite 502  
Montreal, Quebec  
Canada H3C 2N5 

Back to top

The MY VIRTUAL MODEL™ logo is a trademark owned by My Virtual Model Inc.
